# Bruno Alejandro Bahamondes Pérez

#### **Personal Information**

o Address: Estación Central, Santiago, Región Metropolitana, Chile.

o Phone Number: +56 9 9199 9324o Email: bahamondesbp@gmail.com

o Rut: 19.208.517-9

o Date of birth: 22/01/1996

o Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bbahamondes/

# **Summary**

Bilingual Analyst Programmer with over two years of experience in the area. I'm experienced in managing Hadoop environments, troubleshooting JVM issues, configuration and network issues. I'm familiar with both Hortonworks and Cloudera environments with varying degrees of expertise in the Hadoop components. I'm also experienced in scripting. Mostly self taught on Bash and Python

# **Work History**

Cloudera

Customer Operations Engineer

2019-Present

Bilingual Technical Support for Data in motion services like Apache Nifi, YARN, Spark, Kafka, Nifi Registry and Minifi.

Hortonworks Chile

Associate Technical Support Engineer

2018-2019

Gave bilingual technical support for Hadoop services including HDFS, Zookeeper, YARN, etc; managing customer expectations and critical situations.

Bprog LTDA Chile

Software Developer 2017–2018

Had to meet with clients, talk with them and offer a solution that best solves their problem. Had to work under pressure to meet deadlines.

### Qualifications

Instituto Profesional DuocUC

Chile

<sup>1</sup> Ingenieria Informatica

2019-Present

Instituto Profesional DuocUC

Chile

Analista Programador Computacional

2015-2017

#### Skills

o Hadoop Ecosystem

HDFS, MapReduce, YARN, Apache NiFi, Hive, Kafka, Zookeeper, Spark, Kerberos, JVM Troubleshooting.

o Languages

Fluent English. Native Spanish

o Programming Languages

Advanced knowledge on: C#, Python. Notions on: Java.

o Database Languages

SQL, PL/SQL, Transact-SQL.

o Web Development Languages

Advanced knowledge on: PHP, Django, Jquery, JavaScript, LATEX.